dotloop.com 2016-03-23

# dotloop - peoplework, not paperwork.

**Our Commitment To Privacy**  
This Privacy Policy applies to www.dotloop.com owned and operated by Dotloop, Inc. Your privacy is important to us. In order to better protect your privacy, we provide this notice (the "Policy") explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. By providing personal information to Dotloop, Inc. ("Dotloop", "We", "Us", or "Our") through our website www.dotloop.com, you agree and consent that we may collect, use, and disclose your personal information in accordance with this Policy. To make this Policy easy to find, we make it available on our homepage.

Dotloop, Inc. has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, [http://www.dotloop.com](http://www.dotloop.com/) and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile application. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact [TRUSTe here.](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)

**The Information We Collect**  
This Policy applies to all information collected or submitted on dotloop.com. We consider "personal information" to mean information about an identifiable individual. The type of personal information collected on the website includes, but is not limited to: Name, Address, Email Address, Phone Number, and your involvement in a real estate transaction. We also collect billing information such as credit card numbers. Contact information of other people may also be collected from or submitted by you during the transaction process or for other communication purposes. The same types of information previously described in this paragraph will also apply to other people's information. 

**The Way We Use Information**  
We use the information you provide when processing or completing a transaction on dotloop to communicate to the other parties involved. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete a transaction, where required or permitted by law, or as set forth in this Policy (see Information Sharing section below). We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may share your personal information with third parties who may offer services that may be of interest ("Third Party Sharing").

Similarly, we use the information you provide about someone else for communications required during the transaction process. If you provide personal information about your client(s) to us for the purpose of completing a transaction, you represent and warrant that you have obtained their consent to do so. Such information may be shared with outside parties to complete a transaction for Third Party Sharing.

If you wish to opt out of such Third Party Sharing, please email us with your request at [support@dotloop.com](mailto:support@dotloop.com). We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. dotloop may use the information collected from you to provide you with additional information about dotloop's services, partners, promotions, and events. Every marketing email from dotloop contains instructions on how to opt out of receiving further marketing emails.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. We may collect information such as occupation, language, zip code, area code, unique device identifier, location, and the time zone where dotloop.com is used so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our website to better suit our customers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form.

At times dotloop.com may make certain non-identifying information available to strategic partners that work with dotloop.com to provide products and services. Such information helps us make our advertising and email communications more relevant to your interests and needs.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as improving system performance or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.

In the event that we enter into a business transaction, such as a merger with or an acquisition by another company, or a sale of some or all of our assets, your personal information may be among the assets that are transferred or disclosed in connection with such a transaction, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

Finally, we never use or share the personal information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described in this Policy without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

**Our Commitment To Data Security**  
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to help safeguard and secure the information we collect online. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). You should note, though, that the internet is not a 100% secure environment. There is no guarantee that information you provide or that we maintain may not be accessed, copied, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at [support@dotloop.com](mailto:support@dotloop.com)

**How You Can Access Your Information**  
You can retrieve, correct or update your personal information by accessing your account on dotloop.com or by contacting us at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Opt out Preferences and Service Related Emails**  
We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do no have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

**Tracking Technologies / Cookies**  
Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Dotloop, Inc. and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users' settings. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may not be possible.

  * **Log Files**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or click stream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

We use local storage objects such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

  * **Behavioral Targeting**

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Information Sharing**  
Normally, we will not disclose personal information unless you have authorized the disclosure. There are some circumstances where we may disclose personal information without consent. Such circumstances include where we are required or permitted by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of an identifiable person or group; or where the information is public. We will not disclose more information than required or permitted.

We endeavor to ensure that your personal information is as accurate as necessary and generally retain personal information as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected.

We operate in the United States. Any information provided through dotloop.com will be processed and stored in the United States, where privacy laws may offer different levels of protection from those in Canada or other countries and personal information may be subject to access by and disclosure to law enforcement agencies in the United States. We may also share personal information with organizations that perform services on our behalf. We require those service providers to take the necessary precautions to protect the personal information. 

In most cases and subject to legal or contractual restrictions, you are free to refuse or withdraw your consent at any time upon reasonable, advance notice.

**Changes to the Policy**  
By providing information to us, you signify your consent to this Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy or the Terms of Use, please do not use the website, or provide your information to us. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time and we will update this page to reflect the date of the last update. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of our Services following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. The date of the last update is located at the bottom of this Policy.

**Links to Third Party Websites**  
Our website may contain "links" to other websites. We cannot be responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by other sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these websites before disclosing any personal information to or through them.

Our website and application uses the Google Maps Application Programming Interface (API) and so the Google Privacy Policy is incorporated into this Policy.

**Testimonials**  
We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@dotloop.com](mailto:support@dotloop.com).

**Social Media Features and Widgets**  
Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Invite a User**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend or colleague about our site or share a document, we will ask you for that person's name and email address. We will automatically send email inviting him or her to visit the site or register. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at [support@dotloop.com](mailto:support@dotloop.com) to request that we remove this information from use.

**DotLoop Blog**  
Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

**The Dotloop Data Privacy Guarantee affirms that:**  

  * Dotloop customers own the data they put into dotloop. This includes all customer data, from user information to transaction data.

  * Dotloop will not use this data as part of other Zillow Group products or services unless customers have given us permission to do so. This covers all Zillow Group businesses.

  * Dotloop does not disclose customer data except where required by law or authorized by the customers in question.

This guarantee applies to all data previously entered in dotloop as well as to data entered in dotloop moving forward.

**How To Contact Us**  
Should you have other questions or concerns about this Policy, please email us at [support@dotloop.com](mailto:support@dotloop.com). You may also write to us at:

Dotloop, Inc.  
700 West Pete Rose Way  
Suite 446  
Cincinnati, OH 45203

Last updated: December 7, 2015
